[During sleepless nights, Okita does not count sheep. Instead, he counts Hijikata corpses.]
[Okita was awakened by Hijikata corpse number 4021. And was told he had a visitor...]
["It's Often Difficult to Sleep When You're Engrossed With Counting Sheep"]
(近藤の笑い声)
I see, I see. That's wonderful.
(近藤)いやぁ そうか そうか！
いや それは めでたい！
The entire Shinsengumi will attend the ceremony.
式には ぜひ 真選組 総出で
出席させてもらうよ｡
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)でも 正直 結婚なんて
もう あきらめていたのよ｡
To tell you the truth, I had given up on marriage.
こんな体だし
こんな おばさんだし…｡
My health isn't good, I'm an old lady, and no one would marry me. I should be grateful.
誰も もらってくれないって…｡
感謝しなきゃね｡
いやいや！ ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿は
昔と なんも変わらんよ｡
No, no, you haven't changed at all, Mitsuba-dono.
(近藤)きれいで おしとやかで
賢くて…｡
Pretty, polite and bright. Sogo often talked about you.
総悟も よく話していたよ…
自慢の姉だって｡
He's very proud of his sister.
もう… 近藤さんったら｡
Oh dear! Kondo-san, flattery will get you nowhere, you know.
おだてても 何も出ないわよ｡
(隊士)おい 誰だ？
あの べっぴんさん➡
Hey, who is that? That babe. What're they talking about?
何 しゃべってんだ？
何 笑ってるんだ？
Why're they laughing?
(隊士)結婚が なんたらと
言ってなかったか？
Didn't they just say something about marriage?
(隊士)んだとぉ!?
お妙さんというものが➡
What?! He already has Otae-san-the son-of-a-bitch!
ありながら 局長の野郎…！
Shh! Keep quiet, stupid!
(原田)ｼｰｯ！ 静かにしろ ﾊﾞｶ!!
(山崎)お前ら 知らねえの？
You guys don't know? That's...
あれ… 沖田さんの
姉上様の ﾐﾂﾊﾞさんだよ｡
Okita-san's sister, Mitsuba-san!
(隊士たちのどよめき)
What?
The one who sends those Super Spicy Rice Crackers every month?
(原田)あぁ… あの 毎月
激辛せんべい 送ってくる…｡
They're too hot to eat.
からくて 食えねえんだよ あれ…｡
But they're so different.
(原田)しかし
似ても似つかんねぇ…｡
It's hard to believe such a polite and quiet person could be Captain Okita-san's...
あんな おしとやかで
物静かな人が 沖田隊長の…｡
だから よくいうだろ！
兄弟のどっちかが➡
That's why they say: if one sibling is irresponsible, the other is very responsible.
ちゃらんぽらんだと もう片方は
しっかりした子になるんだよ｡
(山崎)ﾊﾞﾗﾝｽがとれるように
なってんの 世の中｡
The world balances out that way.
(砲撃音と悲鳴)
まぁ 相変わらず 賑やかですね｡
My, things are always so lively around here.
おぉ 総悟！ やっと来たか｡
Oh! Sogo...you finally made it.
(沖田)すんません… ｺｲﾂ
片付けたら いきやすんで｡
I'm sorry. I'll join you after I take care of him.
総ちゃん ﾀﾞﾒよ
お友達に乱暴しちゃ… めっ！
So-chan, you mustn't. You mustn't be rough with your friends.
ごめんなさい お姉ちゃん！
えぇ～っ!?
I'm so sorry, Sister!
What?!
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊ… 相変わらず➡
You can't compete with your sister, as usual, eh, Sogo?
ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿には頭が上がらん
ようだな 総悟｡
お久しぶりでござんす 姉上｡
It's been so long, Sister. You must be tired after journeying all the way to Edo.
遠路はるばる 江戸までご足労
ご苦労さまでした｡
…誰？
Who is that?!
まぁまぁ… 姉弟 水入らず➡
Well, spend some time alone together. You don't need us.
ｼﾞｬﾏ立ては ﾔﾎﾞだぜ… 総悟！
Sogo, take the day off.
お前 今日は休んでいいぞ｡
(近藤)せっかく
いらっしゃったんだ｡
She came all this way. Show Mitsuba-dono around Edo.
ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿に 江戸の街でも
案内してやれ｡
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ささっ 姉上！
Shall we go, Sister?
局長… 何ですか ありゃ｡
What was that, Chief?
(近藤)ｱｲﾂはな… 幼い頃に
両親を亡くして➡
He lost his parents when he was very young.
それから ずっと あのﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿が
親代わりだったんだ｡
Since then, Mitsuba-dono has been like a mother to him.
ｱｲﾂにとっては
お袋みてえなもんだよ｡
今日くらい いいだろう…｡
Let him be today. A man needs a place where he can let down his guard.
男には ああいう
鎧の紐解く場所が必要なんだ｡
特に ｱｲﾂのように
弱みを見せずに➡
Especially a guy like him...
who never shows weakness and has lived obstinately all his life.
片意地張って 生きてるﾔﾂほどな｡
(山崎)わかりました…｡
Understood. I'll say I never saw today's Okita-san.
今日の沖田さんは
見なかったことにします｡
[Battle Royal Host]
[Note: Spoof of the Battle Royale novel and film and the family style restaurant, Royal Host.]
So this trip to Edo is also to meet your fiancée's family?
じゃあ 今回は 嫁入り先に
挨拶も兼ねて 江戸に？
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)えぇ しばらく
江戸にとどまるから➡
Yes. I'll be staying in Edo for a while, so we can see each other anytime.
いつでも会えるわよ｡
Really? That makes me so happy!
ﾎﾝﾄですか… 嬉しいっす｡
ｳﾌｯ… 私も嬉しい｡
Me, too.
姉上が嫁入りして 江戸に住めば➡
If you wed and live in Edo, we can see each other anytime we want.
これから いつでも
会えるんですね｡
That's right.
そうよ｡
ﾎﾞｸ 嬉しいっす！
I'm...so happy.
ｳﾌｯ 私もよ｡
Me, too.
M-Me, too!
ﾎﾞ… ﾎﾞｸだってよ！ ｸｸｸ…｡
でも ﾎﾞｸ 心配です…｡
But I'm worried. Edo's air is filthy compared to Bushu.
[Note: Bushu was a part of the Musashi province. Which today consists of Tokyo, Saitama and Kanagawa prefecture.]
江戸の空気は
武州の空気と違って➡
汚いですから
お体に障るんじゃ…｡
I'm worried about your health.
見てください あの排気ｶﾞｽ！
Look at all those exhaust fumes.
えっ？
What?
なぁに？ どれ？ 総ちゃん｡
What? Where, So-chan?
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)まぁ 何かしら… くさ～い！
My...what is that smell?
(沖田)ひどい空気でしょう？
Isn't the air awful? I hope it doesn't affect your lungs, Sister.
姉上の肺に
障らなければいいんですが…｡
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)病気なら大丈夫…｡
Don't worry about my illness.
Thanks to the money you send every month, I'm getting full treatment.
総ちゃんの 毎月の
仕送りのおかげで➡
治療も万全だもの… それよりも
総ちゃんこそ 大丈夫なの？
More importantly, are you okay, So-chan?
ちゃんと３食 ご飯 食べてる？
食べてます！
Are you eating three meals a day?
I am.
忙しくても 睡眠
ちゃんと とってるの？
Are you getting enough sleep, even when you're busy?
とってます！
羊を数える暇もないですよ｡
I am. I don't even have time to count sheep.
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)皆さんとは 仲よく
やっているの？
Are you getting along with everyone? You're not being bullied, are you?
いじめられたりしてない？
う～ん… たまに
嫌なﾔﾂもいるけど➡
Well, at times, some of the guys are nasty, but I don't give in.
ﾎﾞｸ くじけませんよ！
じゃあ お友達は？
How about friends?
Do you have a close friend you can confide your problems in?
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)悩みの相談ができる
親友はいるの？
大親友の 坂田 銀時…｡
(銀時)なんでだよ！
My good friend, Gintoki Sakata-
What's up?
おい いつから ｵﾚたち
友達になった？
Hey, since when did you and I become friends?
旦那… 友達ってやつは➡
Master, you don't become friends because you decide to, it just happens.
今日からなるとか
決めるんじゃなく➡
いつの間にかなってるもんでさぁ｡
And friends just happen to leave, too.
そして いつの間にか
去ってくのも 友達だ｡
すみません ﾁｮｺﾚｰﾄﾊﾟﾌｪ
３つ お願いします｡
Excuse me. Three chocolate parfaits, please!
We're friends, or rather, he's like a younger brother to me.
友達っていうかぁ もう
ｵﾚとしては もう➡
弟みたいな？ まぁ
そういう感じかな？
That's how it seems. Right, Soichiro-kun?
なぁ 総一郎君！
総悟です｡
It's Sogo.
こういう細かいところに
気が回るところも➡
I like how he pays attention to details. Right, Soichiro Yagami-kun?
[Note: Name of Light's father from DEATH NOTE.]
気に入っててね… ねっ
夜神 総一郎君！
総悟です｡
まぁ… また この子は➡
It's Sogo.
My, so my younger brother made friends with an older person again.
こんな年上の方と…
総ちゃん あなた 昔から➡
You've always surrounded yourself with older people.
年上ばかりに囲まれて｡
That's okay. I'm still an eighth-grader in summertime at heart.
大丈夫です 頭はずっと
中ニの夏の人なんで｡
中ニ？ よりによって お前
世界でいちばん ﾊﾞｶな中ニ？
Eighth grade?
Of all things... Were you the most stupid eighth-grader in the world, Takeshi Kaga-kun?
[Note: Takeshi Kaga is the Iron Chef Japan host.]
そりゃねえだろ 加賀 丈史君！
総悟です｡
It's Sogo.
Master, please. Sister has lung disease.
旦那… 頼みますぜ｡
姉上は 肺を患ってるんでさぁ｡
She can't handle stress.
ｽﾄﾚｽに弱いんです…｡
I don't want to needlessly worry her. Please do a better job of playing my friend.
余計な心配を
かけさせたくないんでぇ｡
もっと しっかり
友達 演じてくだせえ！
Huh? Just a minute, Sister, what're you doing? Hello?
あれ？ ちょっと おねえさん
何やってんの？ ねぇ｡
おねえさ～ん!? それ ﾀﾊﾞｽｺ～！
Sister! That's Tabasco!
As a show of my appreciation for you taking care of So-chan,
総ちゃんが
お世話になった お礼に➡
私が特別おいしい食べ方を
お教えしようと思って｡
I thought I'd show you an especially delicious way to enjoy this.
辛いものは お好きですか？
Do you like spicy foods?
いやぁ 辛いも何も 本来
辛いものじゃないからね これ｡
Well, this is...not something that's supposed to be spicy.
(咳込み)
やっぱり 嫌いなんですね｡
So you...
don't like it...even though you're So-chan's friend.
総ちゃんの友達なのに…｡
《友達 関係なくねえ？》
Being friends has nothing to do with it.
(沖田)好きですよね？ 旦那｡
You like it, right, Master?
《なんだ？ これは…
今までにないﾀｲﾌﾟだ｡
What is this? I've never met anyone like this. If I'm not careful...
I might like it, now that I think about it.
Spicy foods are good for you.
なんか 下手ふむと…》
They enhance your appetite.
私も病気で食欲がないとき
何度も助けられたんです｡
Spicy foods have helped me many times when I was ill and had no appetite.
でも ﾊﾟﾌｪ２杯も食べたから➡
But I've already had two parfaits, so my stomach's full...
ちょっと お腹いっぱいに
なっちゃったかなぁ なんて…｡
you know.
(咳込み)
旦那！
Master!
Get me some water!
み… 水を用意しろ～！
み… 水も飲むなってか？
She wants me to eat this without water?!
ｸｯ…｡
姉上！
Sister!
んがぁ～！
うおぉぉ～！
姉上 姉上！
しっかりしてくだせえ!!
Sister! Sister! Please say something!
大丈夫 さっき食べたﾀﾊﾞｽｺ➡
I'm fine. I just spit out the Tabasco I just ate.
吹いちゃっただけ｡
なうしか！
Nausicaa!!
[Note: The voice actress for Mitsuba also voiced Nausicaa from Nausicaa The Valley of the Wind.]
(土方)ｸｯ… 何じゃ こりゃ…｡
What the hell is this?! Water... Water...
み… 水！
(山崎)差し入れです！
It's a gift. "Super Spicy Rice Crackers" from Okita-san's sister.
沖田さんの姉上様からの
激辛せんべい｡
(土方)山崎 ﾃﾒｴ ﾅﾒてんのか!?
なんでｱﾌﾛ？
Yamazaki, are you mocking me? What's with that afro?
(山崎)ｵﾚに怒らんでください！
怒るならﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿に…｡
Don't get angry with me. Be angry at Mitsuba-dono.
(山崎)副長 なんで
会われなかったんですか？
Vice-Chief, why didn't you go see her?
(山崎)局長に聞きましたよ｡
Chief told me about it.
(山崎)副長と 局長
そして ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿は➡
You, Chief and Mitsuba-dono were friends back when you were in the Bushu countryside,
真選組結成前 まだ武州の
田舎にいた頃からの友人だと｡
before the Shinsengumi was formed.
(山崎)不審船調査なんて
つまらん仕事➡
You should've let me take care of the trivial job
ｵﾚに任せて
ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿に会えばよかったのに…｡
of checking out suspicious vessels and gone to see Mitsuba-dono.
(土方)最近の攘夷浪士たちの
ﾃﾛ活動に用いられる武器が➡
The kind of weapons the Anti-Foreigner Faction has these days
以前とはﾓﾉが違ってきている｡
are different from those of the past.
(土方)廃刀令のご時世に 民間で➡
In these times of the Sword ban, it's not easy for civilians to acquire goods like that.
そんな えものを手に入れるのは
容易なことじゃねえ｡
幕府の誰かが横流しして➡
I'm positive someone in the Bakufu government is diverting the goods through illegal channels
闇取引してるのは
間違いねえんだ｡
and selling them on the black market.
(山崎)副長…
ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿と何かありましたか？
Vice-Chief. Did something happen between you and Mitsuba-dono?
(土方)あぁ… 何かある…
間違いねえ｡
Yes, there's something there. I just know it.
(山崎)やっぱり 焼けぼっくいに
火がついて～みたいな？
I knew it. There's still fire in the embers.
(土方)あぁ
火がついたら大変なことに…｡
Yes. If there's a fire, it'll be big trouble.
あれ？ おっ？
いや… なわけねえだろう！ ﾃﾒｴ｡
Seriously? Huh? No, it's nothing like that! Dammit!
なに言ってんだ！ 殺すぞ ｵﾗ!!
What're you talking about? I'll kill you. Why're you wearing an afro?
なんでｱﾌﾛなんだ？ お前…
おい 殺すぞ！
I'll kill you. For Pete's sake.
ったく！
ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿 結婚するらしいですよ｡
It looks like Mitsuba-dono is going to get married.
だから 関係ねえって
言ってんだろう！ ｱﾌﾛ おい!!
It's none of my businesses, I keep telling you! That afro!
なんでｱﾌﾛなんだよ 殺すよ ﾎﾝﾄ｡
Hey! Why're you wearing an afro? I really will kill you!
(山崎)相手は貿易商で
たいそうな長者とか！
Her fiancé is a merchant and a millionaire. A real Cinderella story, I'd say.
玉の輿ですなぁ…｡
知るかよ｡
What do I care? What's with the "I'd say"? You piss me off.
なんだよ ｢ですなぁ｣って！
ｲﾁｲﾁ 腹立つな ｺｲﾂ… ったく!!
You only notice the useless things.
監察が くだらねえことばっか
観察してんじゃねえよ！
だいたい なんでｱﾌﾛなんだよ｡
あっ あぁ…｡
In the first place, why're you wearing an afro?
副長！ あれ!!
Vice-Chief, over there...!
I had a fun time today.
(沖田)今日は楽しかったです｡
So-chan, thank you for everything.
[Note: The bag Mitsuba is holding is from JUMP FESTA.]
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)総ちゃん
いろいろ ありがとう｡
(沖田)今日くらい
ｳﾁの屯所に泊まればいいのに｡
You should stay at our headquarters, at least for today.
なにも 婚約者の家に
泊まらずとも…｡
You don't have to stay over at your fiancée's place.
ごめんなさい… こちらで➡
I'm sorry. There are a lot of things I need to take care of.
いろいろ やらなければ
ならないことがあって…｡
坂田さんも 今日は
いろいろ つきあってくれて➡
[Note: Gin is wearing a Chopper hat. Okita is wearing Usopp glasses. (from One Piece)]
Sakata-san, thank you very much for your company today.
ありがとうございました｡
あぁ 気にすんな｡
Don't mention it.
じゃあ 姉上 ここで…｡
All right, Sister, I'll say good-bye here. Please go on in.
先に入ってください｡
えぇ｡
All right.
Oh, So-chan.
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)あぁ 総ちゃん…｡
あの… あの人は…｡
How is...he...?
(沖田)野郎とは会わせねえぜ｡
I won't let you see that bastard.
(沖田)今朝方も何も言わずに
仕事に出ていきやがった｡
He left this morning on a job without saying anything.
薄情な野郎で…｡
He's a cold-hearted bastard.
♪♪～
仕事 相変わらずみたいね｡
Work comes first, as usual, it seems.
おいおい…
勝手に巻き込んどいて➡
He gets me mixed up in this and then just up and leaves.
勝手に帰っちまいやがった｡
ごめんなさい｡
Forgive him. He's a selfish child.
わがままな子で…｡
私のせいなんです｡
It's my fault.
幼くして両親を亡くした あの子に
寂しい思いをさせまいと➡
He lost his parents when he was very young,
so in order to keep him from feeling lonely, I indulged him while raising him.
甘やかして育てたから…｡
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)身勝手で頑固で
負けず嫌いで➡
He's selfish, bull-headed, and hates to lose.
そんなんだから昔から独りぼっち｡
That's why he was always a loner even back then.
友達なんて
１人もいなかったんです｡
He didn't have a single friend.
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)近藤さんに出会わなかったら
今頃どうなってたか…｡
If he hadn't met Kondo-san, who knows how he might've turned out.
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)今でも
まだちょっと怖いんです｡
Even now, I'm a bit anxious. Is he doing okay?
あの子 ちゃんとしてるのかって｡
ﾎﾝﾄは あなたも お友達なんかじゃ
ないんでしょう？
You're not really his friend, are you?
ｱｲﾂが ちゃんとしてるかって？
Is he doing okay? How could he be?
してるわけないでしょ
そんなもん！
仕事さぼるわ Ｓに目覚めるわ…｡
He skips work, he's awakened his sadistic side, he's committed scandal,
不祥事 起こすわ Ｓに目覚めるわ｡
and he's awakened his sadistic side...
ろくなもんじゃねえよ！
あのｸｿｶﾞｷ!!
He's no good. That shitty brat.
いったい
どういう教育したんですか！
What kind of education did you give him?
友達くらい選ばなきゃいけねえよ｡
He needs to choose his friends.
ｵﾚみたいのと つきあってたら➡
If he hangs around with people like me, nothing good is going to happen.
ﾛｸなことにならねえぜ
おたくの子！
ﾌﾌｯ… おかしな人｡
You're a funny man. But...
でも…｡
ん？
No wonder he's attracted to you. You're sort of similar.
どうりで あの子が懐くはずだわ｡
何となく あの人に似てるもの｡
あぁ!? 似てる？
Huh? Similar?
(ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ音)
(土方)
おい ﾃﾒｴら そこで何やってる！
Hey.
What're you people doing here?
この屋敷の…｡
This mansion...
と… 十四郎さん…｡
Toshiro-sa...
(咳込み)
あっ…！
Hey! Get ahold of yourself. Hey!
おい！ しっかりしろ!!
おい!!
(山崎)ようやく
落ち着いたみたいですよ｡
She seems to finally be resting.
(山崎)体が悪いとは
聞いちゃいたが➡
I heard she was in poor health...
but it appears her condition is worse that we thought.
ｵﾚたちが 思ってるより
病状は よくねえみたいで…｡
(山崎)それより 旦那｡
ｱﾝﾀ なんで ﾐﾂﾊﾞさんと？
But that aside, why were you with Mitsuba-san, Boss?
なりゆき｡
そういう お前は どうして ｱﾌﾛ？
It just happened.
What's with that afro?
なりゆきです｡
どんな なりゆき？
It just happened.
How did that "just happen"?
そちらさんは…➡
For you...it doesn't look like "it just happened."
なりゆきって感じじゃ
なさそうだな｡
ﾂﾗ 見ただけで 倒れちまうたぁ➡
The way she collapsed just from seeing your face...
Something major must've happened between you two.
よほどのことが
あったんじゃねえの？ おたくら｡
ﾃﾒｴには 関係ねえ｡
It's none of your business.
すんませ～ん｡
Forgive me.
It's boorish of me to stick my nose into what happens between a man and a woman.
男と女の関係に
他人が 首 つっこむなんざ➡
ﾔﾎﾞですた～｡ ﾎﾝﾄ すんませ～ん｡
I'm really sorry.
Don't stop there, Boss.
ﾀﾞﾒですよ～ 旦那！
ああ見えて 副長 ｳﾌﾞなんだから！
The Vice-Chief may not look it, but he's very naïve.
関係ねえっつってんだろうが～!!
I said it's none of your business! What are you doing here, anyway?!
だいたい なんで ﾃﾒｴ
ここに いるんだ～!?
副長 おち… 落ち着いて！
隣に 病人が いるんですよ～!!
Vice-Chief, calm down! There's an ill person right next to you!
Shut up! What're you wearing an afro for, anyway?!
うるせえ～！ だいたい ｵﾒｴは
なんで ｱﾌﾛなんだよ～！
(蔵場)皆さん｡
Everyone.
I'm sorry I couldn't do more for you.
(蔵場)なんの お構いもせず
申し訳ございません｡
(蔵場)ﾐﾂﾊﾞを 屋敷まで
運んでくださったそうで➡
I'd like to thank you for carrying Mitsuba to my mansion.
お礼 申し上げます｡
I run the trading company "Tenkaiya." My name is Toma Kuraba.
私…
貿易業を 営んでおります➡
転海屋 蔵場 当馬と申します｡
ﾐﾂﾊﾞさんの 旦那になる
お人ですよ｡
He's going to become Mitsuba-san's husband.
体に障るゆえ
あまりあちこち 出歩くなと➡
I had warned her against walking around town because it would affect her health.
申していたのですが➡
My Mitsuba has caused you all a great deal of inconvenience.
今回は ｳﾁの ﾐﾂﾊﾞが
とんだ ご迷惑を…｡
(蔵場)もしかして 皆さん
その制服は 真選組の方ですか？
Your uniform...might you be members of the Shinsengumi?
Then you must be friends with Mitsuba's younger brother...
ならば ﾐﾂﾊﾞの弟さんの ご友人？
They're not my friends.
(沖田)友達なんかじゃねえですよ｡
(蔵場)総悟君｡
総悟君 来てくれたのか…｡
Sogo-kun.
Sogo-kun, so you came. Mitsuba-san is...
ﾐﾂﾊﾞさんが…｡
土方さんじゃ ありやせんか｡
Well, if it isn't Hijikata-san. How odd for us to meet here.
こんなところで お会いするとは
奇遇だなぁ｡
どのﾂﾗ 下げて
姉上に 会いにこれたんでい？
How dare you come to see Sister.
You misunderstand, Okita-san! We came because...
(山崎)違うんです 沖田さん！
ｵﾚたちは ここに…！
ぶは～っ!!
ｲﾀﾀﾀ… あぁっ…！
Ow, ow, ow...
(土方)ｼﾞｬﾏしたな｡
Sorry to bother you.
ひ… 土方さん！ いいんですか!?
Hi-Hijikata-san... Are you sure about this?
♪♪～
((ﾐﾂﾊﾞ:総ちゃん！ 総ちゃん！
So-chan. So-chan!
総ちゃん 稽古の時間よ｡
So-chan, it's time for practice.
どうしたの？
What's the matter? You usually get up early by yourself to go to the dojo.
いつもは 勝手に早起きして
道場に行くのに…｡
Did something unpleasant happen?
ｲﾔなことでも あったの？
むかつくﾔﾂが いるんです｡
There's a guy who pisses me off.
The one who began coming to the dojo recently?
この間から
道場に 来てるっていう人？
ﾎﾞｸより 後輩のくせに ﾀﾒ口だし
生意気だし…｡
He's junior to me, but he's cocky and talks like we're equals.
ｱｲﾂが来てから 近藤さんも
あんまり かまってくれないし…｡
Since he came, Kondo-san doesn't pay much attention to me.
I've had it. I don't want to go to the dojo.
もう ﾔﾀﾞ…｡
ﾎﾞｸ 道場 行きたくないっす｡
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)総ちゃん…｡
So-chan...
Okita Senpai. Time for practice.
沖田先輩… 稽古の時間っす｡
(沖田)ﾃﾒｴ！
なんで 人んちに来てんだよ!!
You! Why're you at my house?!
You jerk!
(沖田)この… くっ…！
(土方)近藤さんに➡
Kondo-san said to bring you.
連れてこいって 頼まれたっす｡
Lemme go, you jerk!
(沖田)離せよ… この…！
Ow, ow, ow!
ｲﾀﾀﾀﾀ…!!
さぁ 一緒に行きましょうか 先輩｡
C'mon, lets go, Senpai.
You! Is this any way to treat your Senpai?! Damn you!
ﾃﾒｴ！ それが
先輩に対してとる態度か！ ﾃﾒｴ!!
(笑い声)
(沖田)気にくわねえ…｡
I don't like him.
♪♪～
あ～ あ～ あ～ ちょっと～!!
ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿～！
Just a minute! Mitsuba-dono!
(近藤)ﾀﾞﾒだって！
そんなに 唐辛子 かけたら！
You shouldn't put on so much chili pepper!
(近藤)何回 言ったら わかるの！
体に障るって～!!
How many times do I have to tell you? It's bad for your health!
だって おいしいんだもの｡
だもの じゃないよ！
But it's delicious.
But nothing! It's definitely bad for you! It's completely red!
絶対 体に悪いよ！
真っ赤だもの～!!
Man, today's young people have a strange sense of taste.
まったく
近頃の若者は 味覚が おかしい！
Don't they, Toshi?
なぁ？ ﾄｼ…｡
Toshi!
(近藤)ﾄｼ～!! なに やってんの!?
What're you doing?! What's that you're eating?!
なに それ!? なに 食ってんの!?
It's an IT taste revolution.
[Note: A line from a joke by Japanese comedian Hikomaro.]
味の ＩＴ革命や｡
(近藤)なに 言ってんの!?
What're you talking about?! Who're you trying to mimic?!
なに それ!? 誰のﾓﾉﾏﾈ!?
(近藤)ねぇ ちょっと～!!
Come on! Mitsuba-dono, you shouldn't eat that, I'm telling you!
(近藤)ﾐﾂﾊﾞ殿も
食べたら ﾀﾞﾒだって～!!
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)口の中が
社会保険庁解体や～！
The inside of my mouth feels like the Social Insurance Agency coming apart.
[Note: The Social Insurance Agency (found guilty of insurance fraud) was penalized with mass firings and restructuring. This was a big news item in Japan.]
(近藤)意味 わかんねえから!!
つうか なに それ～!?
That's because you can't taste anything! What's that supposed to mean?
The inside of my mouth is...
[Note: A famous phrase from the movie "Sailor Suit and Machine Gun."]
(土方)口の中が… ﾄﾞﾄﾞﾄﾞﾄﾞﾄﾞﾄﾞ…！
Doddoddoddodotto!
(土方)快感…｡
(近藤)今度は 誰!? ﾋﾛｺ!? ﾏｻﾐ!?
Wonderful!
Now who're you supposed to be?! Hiroko? Masami?
(近藤)お前 どっちにしても ｷﾓｲ!!
Either way, you gross me out.
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞの 笑い声)
I don't like him.
気にくわねえ…))
《沖田:気にくわねえﾔﾂだ｡
I don't like that guy.
Yes, he's a guy I never liked from the beginning.
そう… 昔から ｱｲﾂは
気にくわねえﾔﾂだった…》
Hijikata-san.
(沖田)土方さん…｡
Would you mind giving me a lesson?
一手 ご教授してもらっても
いいですかね？
ﾊｧ… ﾊｧ…｡
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)ごめんなさい…｡
Forgive me.
The ceremony's been postponed because of my health again, hasn't it?
また 私の体のせいで
式が 延びてしまったわね…｡
That's all right. Let's take our time and make you well.
いいんだよ｡
焦らず ゆっくり治そう｡
The ceremony is just a formality.
式なんて
形式にすぎないんだから…｡
I've thought of us as a couple for quite some time now.
ﾎﾞｸは もう とっくに
ｷﾐと夫婦のつもりだよ｡
ありがとう 当馬さん｡
Thank you, Toma-san.
それじゃ
ﾎﾞｸは 仕事があるから行くけど➡
I'll be going now since I have work to attend to.
辛いものとか とっちゃﾀﾞﾒだよ…｡
You mustn't eat spicy foods, okay? It's bad for your body.
体にさわるから｡
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)わかってます｡
I know. I'm not that much of a fool.
私も そこまで ﾊﾞｶじゃありません｡
Well then... I'll be back.
それじゃ また来るよ｡
(物音)
[Note: Bag says "Daioh Buffet" a spoof of the spicy snack, Dictator Habanero.]
ﾌﾌﾌ…！
すごい…！ ﾎﾝﾄに依頼すれば
何でもやってくれるのね｡
Incredible. You really do anything I ask!
万事屋だからな｡
I'm an Odd Jobs.
ほら 食い過ぎんなよ！
痔にさわるぞ｡
Don't eat too much now. It'll give you hemorrhoids.
あなた 私が 痔で
昏倒したと思ってるんですか？
Do you think I collapsed because of hemorrhoids?
おい ｵﾒｴもどうだ？
ﾊﾞﾅﾅとかもあるぞ｡
Hey, you want something, too? I have bananas.
(山崎)いえ 結構です｡
隠密活動のときは➡
No thank you. I always carry sausages with me on secret agent activities.
常に ｿｰｾｰｼﾞを携帯しているので｡
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)…あれ？ 山崎さん？
なんで こんなところに？
Oh, Yamazaki-san?
What are you doing here?
(山崎)しまったぁぁっ!!
Oh no!
ｲﾃﾞ ｲﾃﾞﾃﾞ… 痛い… 痛い！
Ow, ow, ow.
(沖田)近ごろ 姉上の周りを
嗅ぎ回らせてるようで…｡
Looks like you've been sniffing around my sister lately.
(打ち合う音)
(沖田)いったい
どういうつもりなんですかね？
What's the meaning of this?
(沖田)これ以上 姉上の幸せ
ぶち壊すのは…！
Don't do anything more to ruin Sister's happiness.
やめてもらいてえんですが…｡
I want you to stop.
(土方)転海屋…
不逞浪士と大量の武器を➡
Tenkaiya.
They are suspected of conspiring with lawless ronin in large weapons deals on the black market.
闇取引しているとの嫌疑がある｡
密輸で仕入れた武器を 浪士どもに
高値で売りさばいてやがる｡
He's been selling weapons at high prices to ronin.
ありゃ 闇商人だ｡
He's a black market dealer.
ｵﾒｴの姉貴の旦那は…
ｵﾚたちの敵なんだよ｡
Your sister's fiancée is our enemy.
あの女は知ってんのかよ？
Does that woman know?
いえ… 副長に 誰にも言うなと｡
No, the Vice-Chief told me not to tell anyone.
Sure you are-you're telling me.
言ってんじゃねえか ｵﾚに！
痛ぇ…！
Ouch! But Boss, you...
いや だって それは旦那が！
ｵﾚがなんだよ？
What about me? Are you making it my fault?
Hijikata-san.
(沖田)土方さん… 攘夷浪士どもが
どんな武器を持とうと➡
Regardless of what sort of weapons the Anti-Foreigner Faction possess,
ｵﾚたちが 叩き斬りゃ
いいだけの話じゃねえですか｡
all we have to do is kill them all. It's a minor problem.
小せえ話だ｡
He can't stay in business unless he's willing to deal with all sorts of people.
清濁併せ飲むくらいの
器量がなけりゃ➡
商売なんてなぁ
やってけやせんよ｡
それに あの人の人柄は
ｱﾝﾀも見たでしょう？
And you saw the kind of man he is and how deeply he is in love with my sister.
心底 姉上に惚れてますよ｡
きっと幸せに…｡
I'm sure he can make her happy.
Are you telling me to look the other way?
そいつぁ ｵﾚに
ﾔﾂを見逃せと言ってんのか？
あら そう聞こえやせんでした？
Is that how it sounded?
今のは
聞かなかったことにしてやる｡
I'll pretend I didn't hear that.
相手は 終わりだ｡
Your lesson is over.
まだ 話は 終わってませんぜ！
We aren't finished talking yet!
寝ぼけてんのか ﾃﾒｴ！
そんな悪党とくっついて➡
Are you half-asleep or something?!
Surely you can't believe your sister will be happy with that...
姉貴が幸せになると思っちゃ…｡
長くねえんです｡
She doesn't have much longer.
もう…➡
I'm told she doesn't...
長ぇこと ねえみたいなんでさ｡
have much longer to live.
やってらんねえよ…
小さい頃から ｵﾚの世話ばっかり｡
I can't stand it.
Since I was little, she took care of me, ignoring her own needs, and even...
自分のことは ほったらかしで
婚期も遅れちまって…｡
But now when she's about to grasp happiness at last...
ようやく 幸せ
手につかんだと思ったら…｡
せめてよ 死ぬ前に 一時でも
人並みの幸せを➡
At least before she dies, I want her to experience happiness like other people.
味わわせてやりてえんですよ｡
見逃せとは言わねえ｡
ちょいとだけ 時間を…｡
I'm not saying to let him go. Just for a little while...
土方さん 姉上が
ずっと独り身だったのは➡
Hijikata-san, Sister stayed single all this time because you were...
ｱﾝﾀのこと…｡
おい…｡
Hey.
The deal goes down tomorrow night.
取引は 明日の晩だ｡
…刀の手入れしとけ｡
Make sure your sword's in good shape.
《気にくわねえ…｡
I don't like him.
ｱｲﾂは いつもそうだ｡
He's always like that.
He just happens to show up and swipe everything I hold dear.
ふらりと現れて ｵﾚの…➡
ｵﾚの大事なもん 全部 横から
かっさらっていきやがる》
(沖田)土方～っ!!
Hijikata!!
((ﾐﾂﾊﾞ:みんな 江戸で
ひと旗あげるってﾎﾝﾄ？
Is it true you're all going to Edo to find success?
(土方)誰から聞いた？
Where'd you hear that?
総ちゃんが
今朝 嬉しそうに｡
So-chan...he looked so happy this morning.
あのﾊﾞｶ…｡
That idiot.
私も… 連れてって｡
Take me...with you...
私は… 総ちゃんの
親代わりだもの｡
I'm...after all, like a parent to So-chan. If I'm not there, that child...
あの子には 私がいないと…｡
それに… 私…➡
And also because...I...
みんなの…｡
Everyone...
(ﾐﾂﾊﾞ)十四郎さんの…➡
I want to stay with...
そばにいたい｡
you, Toshiro-san.
♪♪～
知らねえよ))
Whatever.
(土方)知ったこっちゃねえんだよ｡
What you do is up to you.
お前のことなんざ…｡
気に… くわ… ねぇ…｡
I...don't like...
him...
[Next time: "Perform a German Suplex On a Woman Who Asks If She or the Job Is More Important"]
[The mingling...]
[Of feelings...]
[And swords.]
[Mitsuba's fiancé, Toma Kuraba of Tenkaiya is a black market dealer who sells illegally imported weapons.]
[Hijikata ventures into the enemy's lair alone. And will Mitsuba, whose body is ravaged by illness, live?]